{
    "id": "dd5ab079f025448da16b96f3542a6ef3",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The tree has never …………………… fruit before.",
            "description": "Borne is the past participle of bear.",
            "answers": [
                "bear",
                "bore",
                "borne"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4a561f06c0e34820a930121673f71048"
        },
        {
            "question": "The tree ……………………….. plenty of fruit last year.",
            "description": "The simple past of bear is bore.",
            "answers": [
                "bear",
                "bored",
                "bore",
                "borne"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "dafeb98fda824ba8a5bca06a1275fa85"
        },
        {
            "question": "Alexander the Great …………………….. every opponent between Greece and India.",
            "description": "The past simple of beat is beat. ",
            "answers": [
                "beat",
                "beats",
                "beated",
                "beaten"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "00365e684d794b93a2a1ec1350800bee"
        },
        {
            "question": "A pound of sugar is ………………………. enough for one week.",
            "description": "Barely and hardly mean almost not. ",
            "answers": [
                "barely",
                "bare",
                "hardly"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c86fa3e2d0ea4ec9a4c234c9aa6f15fb"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. barely see him.",
            "description": "Barely has a negative force. You cannot use another negative with it.",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "cannot",
                "can not"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2f1661c520e542539de18dd23aedec1b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Everyone should be aware ………………………… the dangers of smoking.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "about",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "79b93a309f9348c89a4477063cc9cb33"
        },
        {
            "question": "The audience eagerly ……………………….. the speaker’s arrival.",
            "description": "To await is to wait for. ",
            "answers": [
                "awaited",
                "awaited for",
                "waited"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6830fb39c84e4c9d8218a03c0017f9bf"
        },
        {
            "question": "The settlers ……………………… the burning of the fort by destroying a native village.",
            "description": "To avenge is to take vengeance for.",
            "answers": [
                "avenged",
                "revenged"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "f2ecdf91136349c390832fcff8389c98"
        },
        {
            "question": "Avail …………………………… every opportunity to get a good education.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "yourself",
                "yourself of",
                "yourself for"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "928a0bc3d314420598ec5dae37382c51"
        },
        {
            "question": "The audience ………………………. happy with the play.",
            "description": "Audience is a collective noun. Collective nouns are usually used with singular verbs.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b152880aee244294a2bed97790a88c42"
        },
        {
            "question": "The accident ………………………. her of her husband.",
            "description": "To bereave is to lose someone you love.",
            "answers": [
                "bereaved",
                "bereft"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "376090fd9801472b872dd95974016fac"
        },
        {
            "question": "The refugees arrived ……………………….. of their possessions.",
            "description": "Bereft means dispossession.",
            "answers": [
                "bereaved",
                "bereft",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "25e2998f1b1a4123a1fed7ea904ab74c"
        }
    ]
}